<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2026-02-06T00:06:59+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry xml:lang="fa"><title type="html">کشتار ۱۴۰۴</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2026/after-massacre/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="کشتار ۱۴۰۴" /><published>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2026/after-massacre</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2026/after-massacre/"><![CDATA[<p>نزدیک یه ماه پیش، ۱۸ و ۱۹ دیماه ۱۴۰۴ رژیک ایران اینترنت رو قطع و مردم رو کشتار کرد. عدد کشتارها از ۳۶ هزار شروع میشه به بالا. به لطف استارلینک یه تعداد خیلی کمی فیلم می‌رسید بیرون. اما بیشتر هر چه که بود، روایت بود از آدمایی که از مرز رد شده بودن، شنیده از آشنایانی با تلفن بین‌الملل تونستن زیر یک دقیقه تماسی بگیرن، و متن. متن از ایران. متن خیلی مهم بود. شده بود مدیوم اصلی اطلاعات. و می‌گفت چقدر وضعیت بده. ما نمی‌فهمیدیم. تا این که فیلم‌هایی کم‌کم اومد بیرون که غیرقابل تصور بود. آدم‌ها رو بیشتر به هم ریخت. بی‌خبری هم بود. ترس و اضطراب و ناامیدی و خشم بود توی روزای اول تا این که آدما(ی بیرون) خودشون رو تونستن کمی جمع کنن و شروع کنن به رسوندن صدای بقیه به بیرون. البته هر چند وقت یه بار، با اومدن یه فیلم جدید، اغلب روحشون دوباره و سه‌باره می‌مرد.</p>

<p>منم شروع کردم به دنبال کردن اخبار و پیدا کردرن منبع موثق‌(تر − در غیاب اینترنت و تلفن و پیامک، چیزی به اسم منبع موثق عملا شوخی بود). به حرف این و اون گوش می‌دادم توی توییتر. مصاحبه‌های آدمای مختلف رو تو یوتیوب می‌دیدم، هشتگ میزدم و لایک و ریتوییت بود که ازم فوران می‌کرد. اما وضعیت آچمز آچمز بود. نه کاری میشد کرد، و نه میشد کار کرد. هیچ‌کاری نکردن هم کار به آدم حس گناه میداد.</p>

<p>بعد از یکی دو هفته سوراخ‌هایی باز شد از داخل و فیلم‌های بیشتری می‌رسید و عدد کشته‌ها مرتب می‌رفت بالا (هنوز هم که این رو می‌نویسم تعداد دقیق مشخص نیست). ولی خوب حداقل آدما بیشتر تونستن رو خودشون مسلط بشن و برنامه بریزن. البته مسلط خیلی اطمینان داخلش زیاده. واقعیت اینه که تقریبا همه‌ی آدما خودشون رو توی یه تعداد زیادی دوراهی می‌بینن: برم تظاهرات یا نه؟ موافق شاهم یا نه؟ موافق رفتار چپ (اروپا) هستم یا نه؟ R2PforIran یا نه؟ و کلی دوراهی اخلاقی و سیاسی و تکنیکی دیگه. منم مستثنی نبودم. اول تظاهرات رفتم و بعد نرفتم. توی نصف همون تظاهرات جاوید شاه گفتم و توی نصف دیگه نگفتم. چندروزی طرفدار R2P بودم و دیگه نیستم. دوستدار حنگ بودم و الان دیگه نه.</p>

<p>الان اما حس می‌کنم به یه متاحالتی پایداری رسیدم. این که جنگ خارجی نه  و اتحاد تکثرگرایانه‌ی اپوزیسیون بله. بر عکس همیشه که توی این دوراهی‌ها مردد بودم، الان حس می‌کنم این نظر فعلی من راه درستیه. مورد دومش که ۱۰۰٪ درسته و حتی می‌تونم ازش دفاع کنم، اما برای دفاع از عدم جنگ خارجی هنوز نمی‌تونم آدمای احساسی رو قانع کنم (شاید قرار نیست که کسی که پر از احساسه قانع بشه). 
مخصوصا الانی که دارم اینو می‌نویسم، هنوز سایه‌ی جنگ هنوز روی سر کشوره و احتمالی هم که خود من میدم اینه که جنگ میشه. با این که مثل دور قبل با اسراییل، مذاکراتی قراره فردا رخ بده. ولی امیدوارم پشت پرده اتفاقای دیگه‌ای بیفته.</p>

<p>به هر حال. چیزی که به خاطرش این متن رو نوشتم این بود که یادم بمونه که من توی این مدت معتاد شدم. به توییتر و ریتوییت و دیدن یوتیوب. حکم مخدر رو داشت برام. در عمل من رو فلج کرد از لحاظ جسمی و ذهنی. گاها روزهایی بود (مثل همین امروز) که صبح تا شب با پشت قوزکرده و شکم خالی و مثانه‌ی پر و بدن کثیف ساعت‌ها زل‌ می‌زدم به مانیتور و تهش هم هیچی. حتی چیزی رو هم که میدیدم نمی‌فهمیدم. می‌فهمیدم که کلی چیز هست برای خوندن، تحقیق و یادگرفتن. بوکمارکشون می‌کردم. اما هیچوقت عملا دنبالشون نرفتم. یعنی نتونستم خقیقتش. ذهنم چنان خسته می‌شد و تنها می‌تونستم بخوابم تا خودمو برای فردا و راند بعدی آماده کنم. این روتین نه تنها مستاصل‌تر، که حتی خنگ‌ترم هم کرد. در این حد که حتی به ذهنم نمی‌رسید که برای جواب یک سوالم منتظر نشم که ملت توتوریال درست کنن و شاید تو یوتیوب بتونم جوابم رو پیدا کنم. بهم خطور نمی‌کرد که چرا خودم رو مقید نمی‌کنم که سر یه رشته رو بگیرم و همونو یاد بگیرم.</p>

<p>اما خداقل امروز اینو فهمیدم که رفتارم تا حدی اشتباه بود. از الان سعی می‌کنم که حداقل بفهمم که شبکه چطور کار می‌کنه و فیلترینگ و وی‌پی‌ان و  باقی تکنولوژی‌ها چطوری کار می‌کنن. شاید خیری از من به کسی برسه.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[چه کارهایی رو باید و نباید انجام داد و آیا اصلا مهمه؟]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="fa"><title type="html">یک نتیجه</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2025/resolution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="یک نتیجه" /><published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2025/resolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2025/resolution/"><![CDATA[<p>سفر اخیر من به ایران (بعد از بیش از ۵ سال) چند نتیجه برای من داشت:</p>

<ol>
  <li>بخش زیادی از ناراحتی ذهنی من فشارهای درونیه. قبل‌تر فکر می‌کردم که هم‌صحبت نبودن با آدمای هم‌تیپ خودم، عدم فهم محیط و همواره خنگ ظاهر شدن، و یا مشکلات ایران ریشه‌ی اصلی ماجراست.</li>
  <li>بخشی ناراحتی من با خانواده هم ربطی به رفتار اون‌ها نداره. قبل‌تر ناراحتی خودم رو به این موارد نسبت می‌دادم؛ اینکه:
    <ul>
      <li>حتی بعد از قبول حرف‌های من، دوباره کار خودشون رو می‌کنند.</li>
      <li>خودشون رو عمیقا مقید به رعایت رسم‌هایی می‌دونن که به وضوح باعث زحمت هستن.</li>
      <li>درخواست‌هاشون، به هر دلیل، پیش از یک درخواست معمولی، به «گیر» تعبیر می‌شه و بنابراین مرتب احساس می‌کنم که استقلالی ندارم.</li>
    </ul>

    <p>به نظر میاد که مورد اول ممکنه که یک سوتفاهم بوده باشه: اون‌ها کاری که من روش اصرار دارم رو نمی‌کنن چون اولویتشون نیست. اما اگر باشه شاید همون کار رو بکنن. موارد دوم و سوم اما هنوز پا برجا هستن.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>حس من نسبت به خانواده چه درست باشه و چه غلط، چیزی که واضحه اینه که من خیلی از فرصت‌ها رو به خاطر این افسردگی درونی دارم سوخت می‌کنم. بنابراین باید به فکر کنترلش بود…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[که ربطی به تصمیم‌های جدید سال نو ندارد]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Loneliness</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/loneliness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loneliness" /><published>2024-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/loneliness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/loneliness/"><![CDATA[<p>Some problems are very easy to resolve, but, for whatever reason, they stay unresolved. What pisses me off so badly is that these ones also those that tend to reoccur. And so frequently so. To the extent that they don’t seem simple anymore, but rather gigantic, challenging, and unresovlable ones. I wish these issues had physical forms, so that I could place them on a big stone and hammer them down into little scattered pieces. To get rid of them, once for all.</p>

<p>I wonder if having and dealing with such problems is the <em>normality</em> of life. Aren’t we, humans, supposed to dominate our problems, solve them, and create new better environments? Why doesn’t it happen then? Am I the problem? Am I even doing my normal human stuff? It seems like all I’m doing is to add more pain and agony to my surronding. What the hell am I doing and why is this happening? I wish I had a place to go and talk freely and openly, and get consoled. Frustrating!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[More nagging]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Motivated by Fear</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/fear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motivated by Fear" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/fear</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/fear/"><![CDATA[<p>I often hear that to do science one must “like it” or “have fun with it”. But I just don’t get it. I understand why doing stuff becuase of its fun is so advantageous. But, not everyone does what he/she likes. Often times people do stuff because that’s the most feasible/reliable/safest thing to do.</p>

<p>Recently, I’m facing some sort of a challenge in my research, which is totally expected. Doing a PhD was never supposed to be easy after all. Yet, it prevents me from swithching to projects, and it seems unsolvable (at least with my current level of knowledge). I tried learning new things to be able to solve it, but the truth is, I don’t feel any progress and the sense of stagnation is bothering me a lot lately.</p>

<p>I’ve become fearful. Scared of lack of productivity (over months), and questioning if research is suitable for me. I think I like doing research, but my mental energy says something else. It’s becoming harder and harder for me to approach this challenge. Every time, soon after I start, I feel exhausted.</p>

<p>There are two important things to note:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Sometimes it makes sense to just pick up something else, and place the current work on hold, at some corner of your mind. A new project that is different enought and one that you know you can progress quickly. This helps.</li>
  <li>The “happy academics” are often professors. I have rarely seen any happy <em>junior</em> researcher. I don’t think having fun is the rule. Those who do have fun with research and do have the privilege to do so are lucky. But not everyone is. Not every on is happy. Some, can be motivated by fear, and I think that’s OK.</li>
</ol>

<iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/0z2bufPrU83RRPRaboj3B7?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="PhD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I often hear that to do science one must “like it” or “have fun with it”. But I just don’t get it. I understand why doing stuff becuase of its fun is so advantageous. But, not everyone does what he/she likes. Often times people do stuff because that’s the most feasible/reliable/safest thing to do.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Learning From Trajectories</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/skip_connections/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning From Trajectories" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/skip_connections</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/skip_connections/"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="block-tip">
  <h5 id="note">NOTE</h5>

  <p>This post contains a potentially publishable idea in machine learning. I cannot pursue it due to time constraints. But if you do, please link to this post, or even better, drop me short email. Maybe then I have more free time to investigate this. If you are aware of a publication with similar idea, please also let me know. I can then remove this note and cite them here. Thanks!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In computational neuroscience, it is widely accepted that the momentary state of neurons \(X(t)\) represent the task they are ought to performed. Whether its classifying a previously shown stimlus into a few categories, memorizing it, or predicting what comes next. A goal of the downstream set of neurons is to see that and transform this state \(X(t)\) to that useful target computation \(y\). The key, however, is that the computation must be embedded in the <strong>instanteneous</strong> state. But in reality, the downsteam neurons are not merely some memoryless machines that map \(X(t)\) to \(y\). I suspect that is just a computational simplification. The downstream neurons integrate whatever they see from \(X(t)\), and maintain a trace of it, and potentially compute not just using the momentary input \(X(t)\), but also its (recent) past.</p>

<p>Think about a simple system that has only two neurons, whose momentary rates can be shown as a point in the 2D plane. You are the downstream system which has to infer the state to do computation. Let’s say at time \(t\), system is at state \(X(t) = (x_1(t), x_2(t))\). But now, assume, in addition to the state, you have access to some memory of the history of \(X\), i.e., its trajectory. Obviously now you can do more computation inputs can be separated based on their trajectories as well. Simply put, now, not only you care about the state, but aslo <em>how</em> that state was realized. This naturally  gives you the ability to form a context-dependent computaiton.</p>

<div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/trajectory-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/trajectory-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/trajectory-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/trajectory.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

</div>

<p>This might seem trivial in the world of recurrent neural networks (RNN). But what about deep neural nets (DNN)? In fact, DNNs, too, leverage from the trajectory, sort of. Let’s first clarify the concept of time in DNN. Time, at best, is only present through the index of the layer that is processing the input. As the input goes through each layer, it transforms, in the same way it evolves in time in the case of RNNs. Now, what if we garrant the last layer, the readout, access to the intermediate transformations of the input, i.e., its “temporal trajectory”? Then, the last layer will know how exactly an input is transformed, step by step, to give raise to that last activation map. These are exactly the skip connections, or skip pathways <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U-Net">U-net architecture</a>, for instance.</p>

<p>I have highlight that this idea stresses mainly on the importance of the last layer. This is not typical in skip connections (as we see the in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residual_neural_network">residual nets</a>). My gut feeling says that this architecture helps a lot to alleviate adversarial attacks since it can track the evolution of the input and potentially figure out something is not right in the evolution trajectory. Would be very nice to try it out and see if that its really the case or not.</p>

<div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/traj_arch-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/traj_arch-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/traj_arch-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/traj_arch.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="PhD" /><category term="ML" /><category term="NeuroSci" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reinterpretation of the skip connections in deep learning]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Bernstein’s Symposium</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/bernstein-synposium/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bernstein’s Symposium" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/bernstein-synposium</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/bernstein-synposium/"><![CDATA[<p>Bernstein conference of this year had a useful PhD symposium. My takeaway is to be aware of these:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>upward management</strong>: How to manage your advisor</li>
  <li><strong>maintaining colabs</strong>: collaborations aren’t formed by <em>starting</em> them and wishing them to continue. This approach is very similar to mass application during job search, pointless. Figure out <em>what exactly</em> do you want from that collab. You can’t expect them be form a classroom for you. They appreciate if you “upward manage” them and tell them what the should do.</li>
  <li>**Nice people”: Most people are actaully nice. If they can’t help, they’ll say so. But most often they are eager to help. Don’t remember that.</li>
</ul>

<p>Thins to research about:</p>
<ul>
  <li>identity work – read Richard Gao’s blog</li>
  <li>gender diversity</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On scientific writing, interpersonal relationship, upward management, and other things]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">No wrong decision theory</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/no-wrong-decision-theory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No wrong decision theory" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/no-wrong-decision-theory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/no-wrong-decision-theory/"><![CDATA[<p>I think there’s no wrong decision in general. Instead, there are just consequences. Whether or a given consequence make one happy or not, ultimately, depends on the decision, not even the consequence, but on how one can live with the consequence. You can be a risk-taker or a risk-averse – for whatever reason. That strategy plus the consequence would determine your happiness. If we add the golden rule of happiness, i.e.,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>happiness = realization - expectation</p>
</blockquote>

<p>one reinvents the wheel of reinforcement learning. Wow.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A personal opinion]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="fa"><title type="html">تشویق</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/reward/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="تشویق" /><published>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/reward</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/reward/"><![CDATA[<p>امروز خیلی اتفاقی برای یک چیزی که خیلی زحمتی هم براش نکشیده بودم تشویق شدم. در راه خانه به این فکر می‌کردم که همون یک تشویق چقدر روزم رو ساخت و بهم انگیزه داد. اما یهو به خودم اومدم و فهمیدم که از دلایل این که کلا خیلی خوش‌حال نیستم و خیلی خسته‌ام، یکیش احتمالا اینه که کلا تمامی مسیرهای گرفتن تشویق رو بر خودم بسته‌ام. قبل‌تر در مدرسته و دانشگاه یه مکانیزمی مثل امتحان و نمره و رتبه بود (که با وجود پوچ بودنش) به آدمایی که نمره‌شون خوب می‌شد یک جایزه‌ای می‌داد (هر چند که خییییلی‌ها رو قطعا عذاب می‌داد). اما الان، توی مسیر زندگی، جایزه‌های زیادی وجود نداره. آدما باید خودشون به خودشون جایزه بدن که انگیزه‌شون رو از دست ندن. باید به این فکر کنم که چه ‌جایزه‌ای واقعا بهم انگیزه می‌ده و کی باید اونو به خودم بدم.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[امروز خیلی اتفاقی برای یک چیزی که خیلی زحمتی هم براش نکشیده بودم تشویق شدم. در راه خانه به این فکر می‌کردم که همون یک تشویق چقدر روزم رو ساخت و بهم انگیزه داد. اما یهو به خودم اومدم و فهمیدم که از دلایل این که کلا خیلی خوش‌حال نیستم و خیلی خسته‌ام، یکیش احتمالا اینه که کلا تمامی مسیرهای گرفتن تشویق رو بر خودم بسته‌ام. قبل‌تر در مدرسته و دانشگاه یه مکانیزمی مثل امتحان و نمره و رتبه بود (که با وجود پوچ بودنش) به آدمایی که نمره‌شون خوب می‌شد یک جایزه‌ای می‌داد (هر چند که خییییلی‌ها رو قطعا عذاب می‌داد). اما الان، توی مسیر زندگی، جایزه‌های زیادی وجود نداره. آدما باید خودشون به خودشون جایزه بدن که انگیزه‌شون رو از دست ندن. باید به این فکر کنم که چه ‌جایزه‌ای واقعا بهم انگیزه می‌ده و کی باید اونو به خودم بدم.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">On Interdisciplinary Collaboraiton</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/interdisciplinary-collaboration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Interdisciplinary Collaboraiton" /><published>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/interdisciplinary-collaboration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/interdisciplinary-collaboration/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been involved in two different goverment-funded interdisciplinary research projects. Both followed similar theme: one group of experimental folks (hereafter E) are supposed to work with theorists (T). On the paper, it is a good idea. In practive, however, it often fails I reckon.</p>

<p>The obvious thing is these group of people have <em>very</em> different goals, and it doesn’t stop there. Depending on the domain, the distinction between the two groups might be also very multi-layered. Yet, strangly, such collaboration are often formed very organically! Not because of the science, but money: Some poeple from E and T meet, and send a proposal to a major agency for fund, and the organic collaboraiton ends just there! As soon as the money flows each group moves on with their own agenda (plus a few showcase joint publication). They, or at least one of them, don’t listen to learn from thet other because they are deeoly indifferent.  When even one side is not open-minded to listen and learn, the whole thing colapses. Since the reaction of less open group likely demotivates the eager folks.</p>

<p>I personally admire and aspire joint collaboration between E and T groups. And indeed there are some that pass the test of time. In my view, these influencial works follow these patterns:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Both main figures of E and T groups are major figures in their own field,</li>
  <li>they are fairly senior, and already have a fairly large network of collaborators,</li>
  <li><strong>they regocnize a stagnation in their research and reach out to other group for help</strong>,</li>
  <li>both groups are <strong>open</strong> to suggestions and knowledge of the other group (because it is really their problem too).</li>
</ol>

<p>These type of collabs actually flurish, and tend to be influencial, perhaps because patterns 1 and 2 strongly correlate with the experimence, which already makes poeple of both sides to stray less. Also motivation due to 3 shouldn’t be oversought.</p>

<p>There are very few poeple in the world that can form such meaningful collabs. Poor junior researchers that have to live between the tense cultral difference of E and T.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been involved in two different goverment-funded interdisciplinary research projects. Both followed similar theme: one group of experimental folks (hereafter E) are supposed to work with theorists (T). On the paper, it is a good idea. In practive, however, it often fails I reckon.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Succession’s Soundtrack</title><link href="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/succession-soundtrack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Succession’s Soundtrack" /><published>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/succession-soundtrack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arashgmn.github.io/blog/2024/succession-soundtrack/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Succession</em> has a bold and daring soundtrack. The rapid sequence of the first two sets of notes, which defy familiar chords, is followed by a progressively higher cascade of notes spanning three octaves within the first ten seconds. And in case you missed this audacious scatter of notes, the piece offers an even bolder orchestral repetition, ensuring that you, as the audience, are acutely aware of the dark, fast-paced show you’re about to watch. It also ties in perfectly with the show’s theme: such a broad tonal range (three octaves) makes the music unsingable for an average person. How powerful is that? The composer essentially says, ‘I don’t care if you can sing my music or not. It flows, whether you like it or not. And you cannot ignore it. It comes to you, in dark ways you cannot avoid…’</p>

<p>Love it!</p>

<iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/0bSHwuTOZVJUXWT03H9oD2?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[musical bravery]]></summary></entry></feed>